<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <array name="people_descriptions">
        <item>
            Abdul Alhazred, or the Mad Arab, is a fictional character created by the horror writer H.P. Lovecraft.
        	According to Lovecraft\'s \"History of the Necronomicon\" (written 1927, first published 1938), Alhazred was:\n\n

		    \"[A] mad poet of Sanaá, in Yemen, who is said to have flourished during the period of the Ommiade caliphs, 
		    circa 700 A.D. He visited the ruins of Babylon and the subterranean secrets of Memphis and spent ten years 
		    alone in the great southern desert of Arabia — the Roba el Khaliyeh or \"Empty Space\" of the ancients — and 
		    \"Dahna\" or \"Crimson\" desert of the modern Arabs, which is held to be inhabited by protective evil spirits 
		    and monsters of death. Of this desert many strange and unbelievable marvels are told by those who pretend 
		    to have penetrated it. In his last years Alhazred dwelt in Damascus.\" \n\n
		    
		    In 730, while still living in Damascus, Alhazred supposedly authored in Arabic a book of ultimate evil, 
		    al Azif, which would later become known as the Necronomicon.\n

			Those who have any dealings with the Necronomicon usually come to an unpleasant end, and Alhazred was no
			exception. Again according to Lovecraft:\n\n

    		\"Of his final death or disappearance (738 A.D.) many terrible and conflicting things are told. He is said
    		by Ibn Khallikan (13th century biographer) to have been seized by an invisible monster in broad daylight 
    		and devoured horribly before a large number of fright-frozen witnesses. Of his madness many things are told. 
    		He claimed to have seen fabulous Irem, or City of Pillars, and to have found beneath the ruins of a certain 
    		nameless desert town the shocking annals and secrets of a race older than mankind. He was only an indifferent 
    		Moslem, worshipping unknown entities whom he called Yog-Sothoth and Cthulhu.\"
		  </item>
        <item>
            Angstrom is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his only appearance in the 1928
            short story \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is a member of the Emma of Auburn, although his role is uncertain. 
            After Donovan is successful in opening the vault discovered by the crew in R\'lyeh, Cthulhu emerges, killing 
            Angstrom, Guerrera and Donovan. This slaughter is the only mention of Angstrom in the story. 
        </item>  
        <item>
            Atwood is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his first appearance in the 1936 novel 
            At the Mountains of Madness. He is a member of the Miskatonic University physics department, and also a 
            meteorologist. He is part of the Lake sub-expedition and is also butchered by the Elder Things.
        </item> 
        <item>
            Member of the 3-man fishing party, along with Carr, Peter B. and Richmond, John, responsible for dragging a 
            360-pound metallic rock ashore after it crashed into the water off the coast of Potowonket, Maine. The object 
            fell from the sky on Wednesday, August 27, 1913, at approximately 8:30 PM. The fishing party retrieved the object 
            the following Sunday, August 31. 
        </item> 
        <item>
            Castro is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his first appearance in the 1928 short story 
            \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is an \"immensely aged mestizo [...] who claimed to have sailed to strange ports and 
            talked with undying leaders of the Cthulhu Cult in the mountains of China.\" Castro was arrested on November 1, 
            1907 during a New Orleans police raid on a cult ceremony in Louisiana. 
        </item> 
        <item>
            Collins is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his only appearance in the 1928 short story 
            \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is the captain of the Emma of Auburn. En route to Callao, the Emma encounters the 
            heavily armored steam yacht Alert, who orders the schooner to turn back. Collins refuses, leading the Alert to fire 
            upon the Emma using a brass cannon. In retaliation, the crew of the Emma manage to board the Alert and slay all of 
            its members, although Collins and First Mate Green are killed in the battle, leaving Second Mate Gustaf Johansen in 
            command of the crew. 
        </item> 
        <item>
            \"Comte d\'Erlette\" is the title of a French aristocrat and the fictional author of \"Cultes des Goules\", inspired by 
            the ancestral form of Mythos author August Derleth\'s name.
        </item> 
        <item>
            Dana Anne Shirefield, a medical student and archaeologist from Eddington, Massachusetts. 
        </item> 
        <item>
            Danforth is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his first appearance in the 1936 novel At 
            the Mountains of Madness. He is a graduate student at Miskatonic University. As part of the Pabodie Expedition, he 
            accompanies Professor William Dyer on a survey flight over the \"Plateau of Leng\" and goes mad after seeing something. 
            He is described as \"a great reader of bizarre material\", and makes allusions to Edgar Allan Poe and the Necronomicon. 
            According to Fritz Leiber\'s To Arkham and the Stars, he later recovered after being treated with experimental drugs 
            developed by Professor Morgan, though he never recalled the horror he saw on the plateau. Afterward, he became a 
            professor of psychology at the university.
        </item> 
        <item>
            Donovan is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his only appearance in the 1928 short story 
            \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is a member of the Emma of Auburn, although his role is uncertain. When the crew discovers 
            Cthulhu\'s vault in R\'lyeh, William Briden fails to find its opening. Donovan proceeds to feel \"over it delicately 
            around the edge,\" press \"each point separately as he went,\" and is the one who successfully opens the immense door, 
            after climbing atop the structure and finding it to give inward. However once the door has been opened, Cthulhu emerges, 
            killing Donovan, Guerrera and Angstrom. 
        </item> 
        <item>
            The Dunwich Horror is the inhuman child of Lavinia Whateley and the Old One, Yog-Sothoth. It was conceived to free the 
            Old Ones so that they may reclaim the earth. \n\n
            
            Its existence was kept secret by its grandfather, mother, and eventually its twin brother, Wilbur Whateley. It fed on 
            cattle growing up, draining them of blood before devouring them completely. The intense stench of the abomination kept 
            away most passersby.\n\n

			On September 9th, the creature broke free from the Whateley farmhouse, littering the hillside with wooden planks soaked 
			with an odd viscous substance. Barrel-sized tracks were found leading to a meadow where half a herd of cows were drained 
			of blood.\n\n

			In its natural state the being is invisible to the human eye, but a magical spell can render it visible.\n

			Its final words were a cry of mercy to its father, who immediately struck it down with a bolt of lightning. 
        </item> 
        <item>
            Francis Wayland Thurston is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his first appearance 
            in the 1928 short story \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is a Bostonian anthropologist, the grandnephew of George 
            Gammell Angell and the sole heir and executor of his estate. While going through the late Professor Angell\'s 
            papers, he discovered the secret of the Cthulhu Cult, a revelation that probably sealed his doom. 
        </item> 
        <item>
            Frank H. Pabodie is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his first appearance in the 
            1936 novel At the Mountains of Madness. He is a member of Miskatonic University\'s engineering department, and 
            the inventor of a drill \"unique and radical in its lightness, portability, and capacity... to cope quickly with 
            strata of varying hardness,\" used in the disastrous Pabodie Expedition to Antarctica in 1930–31. He also added 
            \"fuel-warming and quick-starting devices\" to the expedition\'s four aircraft.[1] Lovecraft wrote of the name 
            \"Pabodie\", \"I chose it as a name typical of good old New England stock, yet not sufficiently common to sound
            conventional or hackneyed.\" It\'s an alternative spelling of \"Peabody\", a name Lovecraft was familiar with through 
            the Peabody Museum in Salem.[2] \n\n
            
   			[1] Lovecraft, At the Mountains of Madness, p. 4.\n
   			[2] H. P. Lovecraft, Selected Letters Vol. V, p. 228; Joshi, p. 181. 
        </item> 
        <item>
            George Gammell Angell (1834–November 23, 1926) is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his 
            first appearance in the 1928 short story \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is Professor Emeritus of Semitic languages at 
            Brown University who was \"widely known as an authority on ancient inscriptions, and had frequently been resorted 
            to by the heads of prominent museums.\" Angell died suddenly after \"a careless push\" from a sailor \"on a narrow 
            hill street leading up from an ancient waterfront,\" while returning from the Newport boat. At the time of his 
            death, at age 92, he was a childless widower. His research notes on the worldwide Cthulhu cult were discovered 
            after his death by his nephew, Francis Wayland Thurston. 
        </item> 
        <item>
            Green is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his only appearance in the 1928 short story 
            \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is the first mate of the Emma of Auburn. En route to Callao, the Emma encounters the 
            heavily armored steam yacht Alert, who orders the schooner to turn back. Captain Collins refuses, leading the 
            Alert to fire upon the Emma using a brass cannon. In retaliation, the crew of the Emma manage to board the Alert 
            and slay all of its members, although Green and Collins are killed in the battle, leaving Second Mate Gustaf 
            Johansen in command of the crew. 
        </item> 
        <item>
            Guerrera is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his only appearance in the 1928 short 
            story \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is a member of the Emma of Auburn, although his role is uncertain. After Donovan 
            is successful in opening the vault discovered by the crew in R\'lyeh, Cthulhu emerges, killing Guerrera, Donovan 
            and Angstrom. This slaughter is the only mention of Guerrera in the story. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Gustaf Johansen is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his first appearance in the 1928 
            short story \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is a Norwegian sailor \"of some intelligence,\" and the second mate of the 
            Emma of Auburn, whose home address was in Oslo\'s Old Town. En route to Callao, the Emma encounters the heavily 
            armored steam yacht Alert, who orders the schooner to turn back. Captain Collins refuses, leading the Alert to 
            fire upon the Emma using a brass cannon. In retaliation, the crew of the Emma manage to board the Alert and slay 
            all of its members, although Collins and First Mate Green are killed in the battle, leaving Johansen in command 
            of the crew. He dies shortly after his return from the South Pacific in 1925; his papers, found posthumously, 
            provide the only first-hand account of Cthulhu in Lovecraft\'s fiction. His report was written in English to spare 
            his wife from learning the horror of Cthulhu. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Hawkins is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his only appearance in the 1928 short story 
            \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is a member of the Emma of Auburn, although his role is uncertain. When Donovan 
            successfully opens Cthulhu\'s vault in R\'lyeh, the \"quick-eared\" Hawkins is the first to hear the creature\'s 
            \"nasty,slopping sound.\" As the crew continues to listen, Cthulhu emerges, killing Donovan, Guerrera and Angstrom. 
            Hawkins\' fate isn\'t made explicit, but as he did not escape the island with Gustaf Johansen and William Briden, 
            his death by Cthulhu may have simply gone unwritten, or he might have been swallowed with Cthulhu when R\'lyeh 
            re-submerged. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Henry Anthony Wilcox is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his first appearance in the 
            1928 short story \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is an art student studying sculpture at the Rhode Island School 
            of Design, and lives alone at the Fleur-de-Lys Building near that institution. He is described in terms that 
            somewhat recall Lovecraft himself, as a \"thin, dark young man of neurotic and excited aspect [...] The youngest 
            son of an excellent family [...] a precocious youth of known genius but great eccentricity, and had from childhood 
            excited attention through the strange stories and odd dreams he was in the habit of relating. He called himself 
            \'psychically hypersensitive\', but the staid folk of the ancient commercial city dismissed him as merely 
            \'queer\'.\" 
        </item>
        <item>
            Herbert West is the main character in H.P. Lovecraft\’s short story Herbert West-Reanimator as well as the Re-Animator 
            series of films and comics. He is a scientist who creates a formula capable of animating dead bodies. 
        </item>
        <item>
            John Raymond Legrasse is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his first appearance in the 
            1928 short story \"The Call of Cthulhu\". Described as \"a commonplace-looking middle-aged man,\" he is a New Orleans 
            police inspector who led the raid on the Cthulhu cult on November 1, 1907. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Member of the 3-man fishing party, along with Carr, Peter B. and Canfield, Simon, responsible for dragging a 
            360-pound metallic rock ashore after it crashed into the water off the coast of Potowonket, Maine. The object fell 
            from the sky on Wednesday, August 27, 1913, at approximately 8:30 PM. The fishing party retrieved the object the 
            following Sunday, August 31. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Local scientific authority of Potowonket, Maine. Discoverer of the book inside the metallic rock-like object that 
            fell from the sky on Wednesday, August 27, 1913, at approximately 8:30 PM. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Keziah Mason is a witch who studied the secrets of inter-dimensional travel.\n\n
            
            During the Salem witch trials of 1692, an old woman by the name of Keziah Mason was arrested for her suspicious 
            behavior and seeming insight into other worlds. In her testimony to Judge John Hathorne, She confessed to having 
            signed her name in the Black Book of Azathoth, and of her secret name of Nahab. She later disappeared mysteriously 
            from Salem.\n\n

			She is described as having a \"bent back, long nose, and shrivelled chin\" and has a \"croaking voice\".\n\n

			She has an animal familiar; the rat-creature Brown Jenkin, which she trusts to carry messages between her and the 
			devil. She feeds this creature on her blood.\n\n

			When studying physicist Walter Gilman took a room in her house she revealed to him the secrets of inter-dimensional 
			travel in the hopes of taking his soul. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Lake is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his first appearance in the 1936 novel At 
            the Mountains of Madness. He is a professor of biology at Miskatonic University, and the first to discover the 
            Mountains of Madness as a result of his \"strange and dogged insistence on a westward - or rather, northwestward - 
            prospecting trip\" based on his discovery of strange fossils. He also discovers the ancient extraterrestrial 
            specimens that he dubs \"Elder Ones\" based on their resemblance to \"certain monsters of primal myth\" found in the 
            Necronomicon. He reports that his findings in Antarctica confirm his belief \"that earth has seen whole cycles of 
            organic life before known one that begins with Archaeozoic cells,\" and predicts that this \"[w]ill mean to biology 
            what Einstein has meant to mathematics and physics.\" When eight of the Elder Ones turn out to be living creatures 
            rather than fossils, they butcher Lake and the rest of his sub-expedition. For the rest of the story, he is referred 
            to as \"poor Lake\". 
        </item>
        <item>
            Lavinia is the albino daughter of the wizard Old Whateley. Using her father\'s incomplete copy of the Necronomicon, 
            she summoned Yog-Sothoth and he impregnated her. Some time later she gave birth to twins, Wilbur Whateley and the 
            Dunwich Horror.

			Born in 1878, Lavinia loses her mother to an unexplained and violent death at the age of 12. She is in her mid 30s 
			at the time of Wilbur\'s birth. She goes missing on Halloween night 1926, at the age of 48. While no conclusions are 
			spelled out in the story, it is implied Wilbur killed her.

			Lavinia is described as an unattractive albino woman with the characteristically weak Whately chin. She is uneducated 
			except for the bits of ancient lore she gleans from her father\'s books and his limited tutoring. Her appearance is 
			described as \"slatternly,\" and she is prone to wild daydreams.

			She is likely named after the character in Shakespeare\'s Titus Andronicus, who is horribly mutilated and raped before 
			being murdered by her father. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Barnabas Marsh, also known as Old Man Marsh, was the grandson of Captain Obed Marsh. Due to his Deep One ancestry, 
            he is functionally immortal as he has the potential of living indefinitely, though he may still be killed through 
            violent means. This heritage also means he will gradually mutate. He ran the gold refinery in Innsmouth. When Robert 
            Olmstead arrived in Innsmouth his transformation had progressed to the point he was unable to shut his engorged 
            eyes, though he still wore clothing. He was presumably killed during the government\'s attack on the town.\n\n

			He is the great-uncle of Robert Olmstead. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Obed Marsh was a sea captain from Innsmouth. At the height of his career he had command of three ships- the 
            Columbia, the Hetty, and the Sumatra Queen. He learned from the inhabitants of a Polynesian island a ritual to 
            summon the old ones. This was done on Devil\'s Reef then entering into a pact with them, offering human sacrifices 
            in exchange for a constant supply of fish and occasionally golden artifacts. Marsh at some point founded the 
            Esoteric Order of Dagon. He died 1878 and his family continued their control of Innsmouth. He is the 
            great-great-grandfather of Robert Olmstead . 
        </item>
        <item>
            Old Whateley, also known as Wizard Whateley, was a major character in Lovecraft\'s The Dunwich Horror. \n\n
            
            It can be assumed that he summoned Yog-Sothoth to impregnate his daughter or that she was a type of sacrifice.\n\n

			He was the \"aged and half-insane father of Lavinia Whateley,\" about whom the most frightful tales of magic had 
			been whispered in his youth\". Dunwich gossips recall that \"the hills once shook when he shrieked the dreadful 
			name of Yog-Sothoth in the midst of a circle of stones with a great book open in his arms before him.\"\n\n

			He and his daughter occupy a large farmhouse on a hillside, four miles from the Village of Dunwich, Massachusetts, 
			and a mile and a half from any other dwellings. When his daughter was twelve, his wife died, through ill-explained 
			but violent means.\n\n

			He has a large collection of \"rotting ancient books and parts of books\" which he inherited through two centuries 
			of Whateleys. He uses these to \"instruct and catechise\" his daughter as well as his grandson Wilbur. One such book 
			was an incomplete version of the infamous Necronomicon.\n\n

			He died of natural causes on August 2, 1924. Just before his passing he left Wilbur with the responsibility of 
			looking after his twin:\n\n

			\"More space, Willy, more space soon. Yew grows- an\' that grows faster. It\'ll be ready to sarve ye soon, boy. Open 
			up the gates to Yog-Sothoth with the long chant that ye\'ll find on page 751 of the complete edition, an\' put a match 
			to the prison. Fire from airth can\'t burn it nohow.\"\n\n

			Wilbur observed that the whippoorwills, dispersed shortly after his passing, signifying that the creatures did not 
			take his soul.

			His first name is never mentioned, though in Lovecraft\'s later work, Fungi from Yuggoth, he mentions a John Whateley. 
			It is unknown if this is the same man. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Pickman is depicted as a renowned Boston painter notorious for his ghoulish works. His great-great-great-great-grandmother 
            was hanged by Cotton Mather during the Salem witch trials of 1692. (\"Pickman\" and \"Upton\" are, in actuality, old 
            Salem names.[1]) In 1926, Pickman vanished from his home—a date only given in Lovecraft\'s \"History of the Necronomicon\".
             Pickman reappears as a ghoul in The Dream Quest of Unknown Kadath (1926) and aids Randolph Carter in his journeys. \n\n
             
             [1] Joshi and Cannon, p. 219.
        </item>
        <item>
            Robert Olmstead is the narrator of The Shadow Over Innsmouth. His home is in Toledo. Several characters note that 
            his eyes have the same strange quality seen in the infamous Captain Obed Marsh. In the story\'s final pages he 
            learns he is the great-great-grandson of Obed Marsh and a Deep One and in time will become one of the amphibious 
            monsters he witnessed in Innsmouth.\n\n

			His name is never given within the story, but Lovecraft did give it in one of his letters. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Parker is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his only appearance in the 1928 short story 
            \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is a member of the Emma of Auburn, although his role is uncertain. After Donovan is 
            successful in opening the vault discovered by the crew in R\'lyeh, Cthulhu emerges, killing Donovan, Guerrera and 
            Angstrom. Second Mate Gustaf Johansen recounts that during the slaughter, Parker slipped and was \"swallowed up by 
            an angle of masonry which shouldn\'t have been there; an angle which was acute, but behaved as if it were obtuse.\" 
        </item>
        <item>
            Member of the 3-man fishing party, along with Richmond, John and Canfield, Simon, responsible for dragging a 
            360-pound metallic rock ashore after it crashed into the water off the coast of Potowonket, Maine. The object 
            fell from the sky on Wednesday, August 27, 1913, at approximately 8:30 PM. The fishing party retrieved the object 
            the following Sunday, August 31. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Analyzed the the metallic rock-like object that landed off the coast of Potowonket, Maine on Wednesday, August 27, 
            1913, at approximately 8:30 PM. Concluded that a significant quantity of unknown material present in the object 
            rendered classification impossible.
        </item>
          <item>
            Analyzed the book inside the metallic rock-like object that landed off the coast of Potowonket, Maine on Wednesday, 
            August 27, 1913, at approximately 8:30 PM. While studying the volume, Professor Chambers rendered several pages of 
            the book practically illegible. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Analyzed samples of the metallic rock-like object that landed off the coast of Potowonket, Maine on Wednesday, 
            August 27, 1913, at approximately 8:30 PM. Mayfield declared the object a meteorite. 
        </item>
          <item>
            Randolph Carter is one of the most frequently appearing characters in the Cthulhu Mythos. The character is 
            semi-autobiographical, sharing several of Lovecraft\'s biographical aspects as well as his antiquarian tastes and 
            mild nature. \n\n
            
            Randolph is the descendant of the Elizabethan magician Sir Randolph Carter, as well as another ancestor who fought 
            in the crusades, and was captured by Muslims and learned their magical secrets.\n\n

			At the age of ten, he underwent a mysterious experience at his great-uncle Christopher\'s farm and thereafter 
			exhibited a gift of prophecy.\n\n

			Randolph Carter is a graduate from the Miskatonic University.\n\n

			Like Lovecraft, he is an under-appreciated horror writer and published the story \"The Attic Window\" in the January 
			1923 issue of the fictional magazine Whispers. \n\n
			
			He first appearance was in the short story \"The Statement of Randolph Carter,\" in which he and his friend, Harley Warren, 
			attempt to locate the door between the human world and a hell dimension. Though Carter survives Warren was killed by an 
			unseen evil. \n\n
			
			The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath–one of Lovecraft\'s longest tales–follows Carter for several months searching for the 
			lost city of his dreams. The story reveals Carter\'s familiarity with much of Lovecraft\'s fictional universe. Carter is 
			also shown to possess considerable knowledge of the politics and geography of the dream world and has allies there. After 
			an elaborate odyssey, Carter awakes in his Boston apartment, with only a fleeting impression of the dream world he left 
			behind.\n\n
			
			In \"Through the Gates of the Silver Key,\" After obtaining the Silver Key, Carter performed the ritual of the Key in 
			the hills behind Arkham, in the cave known as the Snake-Den. The ritual opened a gateway into a strange realm, which 
			offered up visions of Earth\'s distant past before resolving into an unknown area of strange stone architecture. There 
			Carter encountered \'Umr At-Tawil, The Most Ancient One, whom Carter knew from the writings of Abdul Alhazred in his 
			Necronomicon. \'Umr-At-Tawil addressed Carter telepathically, telling him that he had unlocked the First Gate, and giving 
			him the choice of proceeding to the Ultimate Gate or turning back the way he had come. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Rodriguez is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his only appearance in the 1928 short 
            story \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is a member of the Emma of Auburn, although his role is uncertain. While 
            investigating the island of R\'lyeh with the other crew members, Rodriguez discovers Cthulhu\'s vault atop a monolith. 
            When Donovan successfully opens the immense door, Cthulhu emerges, killing Donovan, Guerrera and Angstrom. 
            Rodriguez\'s fate isn\'t made explicit, but as he did not escape the island with Gustaf Johansen and William Briden, 
            his death by Cthulhu may have simply gone unwritten, or he might have been swallowed with Cthulhu when R\'lyeh 
            re-submerged. 
        </item>
          <item>
            One of the many forms of Nyarlathotep:\n\n
            
            \“…a tall, lean man of dead black coloration but without the slightest sign of negroid features: wholly devoid of 
            either hair or beard, and wearing as his only garment a shapeless robe of some heavy black fabric. His feet were 
            indistinguishable because of the table and bench, but he must have been shod, since there was a clicking whenever 
            he changed position. The man did not speak, and bore no trace of expression on his small, regular features. He 
            merely pointed to a book of prodigious size which lay open on the table.\”\n\n

			He leaves behind him cloven footprints suggesting he has hoofed feet. /n/n
			
			Nyarlathotep is worshipped by witch covens in this form. This is demonstrated in \"The Dreams in the Witch 
			House\" by the witch Keziah Mason.
        </item>
        <item>
            \"Madness was in all the Jermyns, and people were glad there were not many of them.\"\n\n

			This family and their history is the basis of the story The facts Concerning The late Arthur 
			Jermyn and his family.\n\n

			Little is mentioned of the family\'s history prior to the birth of Sir Wade Jermyn. However, it\'s said they were 
			respectable enough and many had portraits, suggesting they have a long history of wealth. Sir Wade Jermyn was 
			a famed anthropologist and explorer who was among the first to explore the Congo region. He kept an extensive
			collection of unusual artifacts and specimens he acquired in his travels. During one of Wade\'s expeditions to 
			the Congo he found a lost city controlled by a race of highly evolved white apes. For unknown reasons these 
			creatures make Wade their king. He took one of their females as his bride and after fathering a child with her 
			they returned to Britain. Although Wade kept her hidden from his staff and the outside world, claiming she is an 
			extremely shy Portuguese girl. He gave her a locket with the Jermyn coat of arms on it. In 1765 he was committed 
			to an insane asylum in Huntingdon.\n\n

			Sir Arthur Jermyn was an English nobleman and the final descendant of Wade Jermyn. Lovecraft described him as a 
			poet and a scholar who had come to accept his appearance. When learning of his ancestry he soaked himself in 
			oil and set himself on fire, putting an end to the Jermyn family. 
        </item>
          <item>
            The first individual of distinction in this family was Captain Obed Marsh of Innsmouth. Like most of the residents
            of Innsmouth he was forced to interbred with the Deep Ones, Pth\’thya-l\’yi. This Deep One ancestry means his 
            descendents will gradually mutate into potentially immortal amphibious humanoids. They had three children, two of 
            whom disappeared under mysterious circumstances. The third, an unnamed daughter, was from an early age educated 
            in France and never knew the dark truth of her conception. The only hint to her ancestry was that her eyes greatly 
            resembled those of the infamous Obed Marsh. Just after the Civil War she married Benjimin Orne and they lived 
            together in Arkham. The two had only one child, a daughter. She at some point moved to Toledo, married and had 
            three children. Two of her children appeared normal, as their father. Douglas however shared his mother\'s 
            unsettling appearance. He would eventually shoot himself in the head after learning the history of his family. 
            Shortly afterword the mother disappeared, presumably returning to the undersea city of Y\'ha-nthlei.\n\n

			The last of the line appears to be Robert Olmstead and his cousin Lawrence. Lawrence is the son of Walter and 
			was committed to a sanitarium in Canton.\n\n

			Other relatives are James Williamson, Eliza Orne, Enoch Marsh, Lydia Menize, Barnabras Marsh, Old Olmstead, 
			Mr. Cleveland, Alice Marsh. 
        </item>
        <item>
            The narrator, who gets to know Pickman while working on \"a monograph about weird art\", describes himself 
            as \"fairly \'hard-boiled\'\", as well as \"middle-aged and decently sophisticated\". He is apparently a 
            World War I veteran: \"I guess you saw enough of me in France to know I\'m not easily knocked out.\"\n

			Thurber is one of several Lovecraft characters to develop a phobia as a result of his horrific experiences;[1] 
			his fear of subways and other underground spaces resembles that of the narrator of \"The Lurking Fear\", 
			who \"cannot see a well or a subway entrance without shuddering\". \n\n
			
			[1] Joshi and Cannon, p. 219.
        </item>
        <item>
            Vulthoom is also known as Gsarthotegga and \"The Sleeper of Ravermos\". In the story, Vulthoom is the Martian
            Aihai\'s equivalent of Satan. Though most rational people believe him to be a myth, he is nonetheless greatly 
            feared by the lower class. In truth he is a mysterious being from another universe, exiled by his fellows there 
            and lying in wait on Mars in the underground city of Ravermos.\n\n

			He plans to take over Mars and then conquer Earth as his next trophy. Because of his vast intellect and advanced 
			technology, he seems godlike, but is in reality merely a very powerful alien who must rest for millennia at a time.\n\n

			While under the influence of the hallucinogenic perfume of an alien blossom, one man envisioned Vulthoom as a 
			gigantic, otherworldly plant, but the being\'s true form is unknown. 
        </item>
          <item>
            A man from from Haverhill, Massachusetts. He came to the Miskatonic University to advance his research in 
            non-Euclidean calculus and quantum physics.\n\n

			He takes board in the reportedly haunted Witch-House, which in the 1600\'s held the witch Keziah Mason. He 
			eventually encounters her.\n\n

			She enters his dreams, attempting to convince him to sign his name into the Black Book of Azathoth. He refuses 
			recalling the horrors which where written of him in the Necronomicon.\n\n

			Jenkin is responsible for the death of the seventeenth century witch Keziah Mason.\n\n

			He was killed when Mason\'s demonic rat, Brown Jenkin, ate his heart. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Wilbur Whateley is a Dunwich inhabitant who plays a central role in The Dunwich Horror. \n\n
            
            In the rural Massachusetts town of Dunwich, Massachusetts on February 2, 1913 at 5 a.m. Lavinia Whateley gave 
            birth to a son, Wilbur Whateley. The date of his birth is noted for the night before the hills rumbled and dogs 
            barked incessantly. Dogs continued to show an instinctual hatred for him for the remainder of his life. Wilbur 
            was immediately recognized for his hideousness, described as a \"dark, goatish-looking infant\".

			He displayed unnaturally rapid physical and mental development: At seven months he could walk unassisted and 
			eleven months could speak. At four and a half, he appeared fifteen and he began to grow facial hair. \"Though 
			he shared his mother\'s and grandfather\'s chinlessness, his firm and precociously shaped nose united with the 
			expression of his large, dark, almost Latin eyes to give him an air of..well-nigh preternatural intelligence,.. 
			something almost goatish or animalistic about his thick lips, large-pored, yellowish skin, coarse crinkly hair, 
			and oddly elongated ears.\"

			At a young age he takes to wearing very coversome clothes. He also has revolting odor, a defining characteristic 
			of the Old Ones. Wilbur\'s voice is distinctive for its \"Strange, resonant fashion which hinted at sound-producing 
			organs unlike the run of mankind\'s\". This presumably allows him to speak the language of the Old Ones. At 15 
			years he had grown to 9 feet tall and showed no sign of stopping. \n\n

			Prior to his grandfather\’s death he left him with the responsibility of raising his twin as well as ensuring he 
			opens the gates to Yog-Sothoth. He could only accomplish this by finding the summoning ritual on page 751 of the 
			Necronomicon. He then travelled to the Miskatonic, Cambridge, and Widener libraries in search of a complete version 
			of this book. They all, under the guidance of Dr. Armitage, denied him access. He was then forced to return to 
			Miskatonic University to steal their copy. This attempt ultimately proves his downfall, when a watchdog savagely 
			kills him. It succeeded soley because Whateley\'s revolver failed to fire. \n\n

			It is then that several disturbing truths of his biology were revealed. In place of blood he had a greenish-yellow 
			ichor. Yellow and black markings covered his back. From the waist down his body was covered in coarse black fur. 
			A sort of rudimentary eye was positioned on each hip. \n\n

			His final words were the excerpt from the Necronomicon which he had been searching. Immediately afterward his 
			corpse disintegrated into a sticky white mass, appearently having no true skeletal structure. Out the window a 
			swarm of Whippoorwills were seen pursuing his fleeting soul. It is unknown if they succeeded in capturing it. 
			Afterward his diary and the contents of his library were transported to Miskatonic University to be studied.  
        </item>
          <item>
            William Briden is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his only appearance in the 1928 
            short story \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is a member of the Emma of Auburn, although his role is uncertain. Briden 
            and Second Mate Gustaf Johansen are the only two men in the crew of 11 who manage to escape R\'lyeh, however the 
            crew\'s encounter with Cthulhu on the island renders Briden insane. By the time the Alert is sighted by the Vigilant 
            several weeks later, Briden has been dead for no less than a week.
        </item>
        <item>
            William Channing Webb is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his first appearance in the 
            1928 short story \"The Call of Cthulhu\". He is a professor of anthropology at Princeton University and \"an 
            explorer of no slight note.\" When Inspector John Raymond Legrasse conferred with a meeting of the American 
            Anthropology Society about the Cthulhu Cult, Professor Webb was the only member of the assembly to be familiar 
            with an idol found during the raid and the ritualistic chants used by the cult, based on his investigation of a 
            \"singular tribe or cult of degenerate Esquimaux\" he encountered \"high up on the West Greenland coast\" in 1860. 
        </item>
         <item>
            William Dyer is a fictional character created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his first appearance in the 1936 novel 
            At the Mountains of Madness. He is a professor of geology at Miskatonic University and a leader of the disastrous 
            Pabodie Expedition to Antarctica in 1930–31. Only his last name is mentioned in the text of Mountains, though he 
            is fully identified in Lovecraft\'s The Shadow Out of Time, where he accompanies an expedition to Australia\'s Great 
            Sandy Desert. 
        </item>
    </array>
    
</resources>
