<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <array name="oldOnes_descriptions">
        <item>
            Azathoth is an Outer God in the Cthulhu Mythos and Dream Cycle stories of H. P. Lovecraft and other authors. 
            Its epithets include \"The Blind Idiot God\", the \"Nuclear Chaos\" and the \"Daemon Sultan\".\n\n
            
            Azathoth\'s precise appearance is only hinted at throughout the Mythos, and indeed may be unknowable by mortal beings. 
            It is described as occupying a position outside of the universe, where it is attended by a cohort of alien servants who 
            continually bathe it with the sounds of pipes and drums. Though it is the ruler and possibly creator of all existence, 
            it is described as \"a blind idiot god,\" oblivious to the universe and the beings within it. Despite this, it does have 
            a will of its own, as it issues commands to Nyarlathotep, its messenger and avatar. \n\n
            
            \"[O]utside the ordered universe [is] that amorphous blight of nethermost confusion which blasphemes and bubbles at 
            the center of all infinity—the boundless daemon sultan Azathoth, whose name no lips dare speak aloud, and who gnaws 
            hungrily in inconceivable, unlighted chambers beyond time and space amidst the muffled, maddening beating of vile 
            drums and the thin monotonous whine of accursed flutes.\"[1]\n\n
            
            [1] H. P. Lovecraft, The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath
        </item>
        <item>
            (The Great Water Lizard) first appeared in Lovecraft\'s short story \"The Doom That Came to Sarnath\" (1920). 
            The being is also part of Lovecraft\'s Dream Cycle.\n\n

			Bokrug is the god of the semi-amphibian Thuum\'ha of Ib in the land of Mnar. The deity slept beneath the calm 
			waters of a lake that bordered Ib and the city of Sarnath. When the humans of Sarnath cruelly slaughtered the 
			populace of Ib and stole the god\'s idol, the deity was awakened. Each year thereafter, strange ripples disturbed 
			the otherwise placid lake. On the one-thousandth anniversary of Ib\'s destruction, Bokrug rose up and destroyed 
			Sarnath (so utterly that not even ruins remained). Afterwards, the Thuum\'ha recolonised Ib and thenceforth lived 
			undisturbed.
        </item>
        <item>
            Cthulhu is an elder god created by H. P. Lovecraft, who makes his first appearance in the 1926 short story \"The 
            Call of Cthulhu\". It is one of the central Great Old Ones of the Cthulhu Mythos, and is often cited for the 
            extreme descriptions given of its hideous appearance, its gargantuan size, and the abject terror that it evokes. 
            After its first appearance in \"The Call of Cthulhu\", Cthulhu makes a few minor appearances in other of Lovecraft\'s 
            works.[1] August Derleth, a correspondent of Lovecraft\'s, later used the creature\'s name to identify the system
            of lore employed by Lovecraft and his literary successors, the Cthulhu Mythos. Cthulhu is often referred to in 
            science fiction and fantasy circles as a tongue-in-cheek shorthand for extreme horror or evil.\n\n

			Alternative spellings for the deity\'s name include Tulu, Clulu, Clooloo, Cthulu, Cighulu, Cathulu, Kutulu, 
			Q\'thulu, Ktulu, Kthulhut, Kulhu, Thu Thu,[2] and it is often preceded by the epithet Great, Dead, or Dread. \n\n
			
			Lovecraft transcribed the pronunciation of Cthulhu as Khlûl\'-hloo.[3] S. T. Joshi points out, however, that Lovecraft 
			gave several differing pronunciations on different occasions.[4] According to Lovecraft, this is merely the closest 
			that the human vocal apparatus can come to reproducing the syllables of an alien language.[5] Long after Lovecraft\'s 
			death, the pronunciation kə-TH\'oo-loo became common, and the game Call of Cthulhu endorsed it. \n\n
			
			[1] \"Cthulhu Elsewhere in Lovecraft\", Crypt of Cthulhu #9.\n
 			[2] Harms, \"Cthulhu\", \"PanChulhu\", The Encyclopedia Cthulhiana, p. 64.\n
 			[3] Lovecraft said that \"the first syllable [of Khlûl\'-hloo is] pronounced gutturally and very thickly. 
 			The u is about like that in full; and the first syllable is not unlike klul in sound, hence the h represents 
 			the guttural thickness.\" H. P. Lovecraft, Selected Letters V, pp. 10 – 11.\n
 			[4] S. T. Joshi, note 9 to \"The Call of Cthulhu, The Call of Cthulhu and Other Weird Stories\"\n
 			[5] \"Cthul-Who?: How Do You Pronounce \'Cthulhu\'?\", Crypt of Cthulhu #9 
        </item>
        <item>
            Crom \'krɒm\ is a fictional deity in Robert E. Howard\'s fantasy tales of the Hyborian Age. He is recognized by 
            the lead character Conan, and his proto-Celtic Cimmerian people.\n\n

			The name Crom is probably derived from the ancient Celtic deity Crom Cruach or Crom Dubh.\n\n
			
			Crom is a grim and gloomy and unforgiving god, ever watching from atop his mountain in dark clouds 
			and obscuring mists, ready to pass a disapproving judgment on any and all. However, he is also said to value 
			courage and tenacity in mortals, even if the human ultimately proves too frail to succeed. Worshipers of Crom 
			claim that he grants his followers strength and endurance and has little patience for weakness. It is commonly held
			that Crom does not answer prayers and disfavors weakness, therefore the name of Crom is typically only invoked 
			during an oath or curse. He is the only member of the Cimmerian pantheon named with any regularity, although 
			another Celtic deity, Manannán mac Lir, is mentioned by Conan in one story. In the story \"Conan the Valorous\" 
			by John Maddox Roberts, Crom is worshiped in and reported to live in a great cave in the east face of the 
			mountain called Ben Morgh in Cimmeria where he (or a giant statue of him) is seated on a throne overlooking 
			the Cimmerian burial grounds known as the Field of the Dead.\n\n

			The Stygian followers of Set placate their deity with human sacrifice and actively venerate serpents, 
			while Ishtar\'s worshippers follow the pleasures of the flesh; in Vendhya, the followers of Asura seek truth beyond 
			the illusions of the physical world, and the Hyborian devotees of Mitra are almost Judaeo-Christian in their 
			merging of asceticism with a commitment to compassion and justice. By contrast, Conan remarks in conversation 
			that it is best to avoid doing anything that would draw Crom\'s attention, as the god brings down only trouble 
			and doom.[1] As a result, he is not so much worshipped in Howard\'s works as invoked in curses and expletives 
			(for instance, Conan exclaims things like \"Crom and his devils\"), or when trying to gather one\'s courage. 
			This does not however imply that he ever does anything, good or bad, to mortals; it is said that his sole gift 
			to men is to bestow them at birth with the courage to survive, persevere, and vanquish adversity.\n\n

			Crom is never depicted as directly intervening or otherwise explicitly causing any event to occur in the original 
			Conan stories by Robert E. Howard. In fact, there is little consistent evidence in his works that Crom, or any 
			other deity, actually exists; the existence of demons and highly advanced aliens are confirmed (as in the stories 
			\"The God in the Bowl\" and \"The Tower of the Elephant\"), while the story \"The Phoenix on the Sword\" implies 
			that Set is one of H. P. Lovecraft\'s Great Old Ones. Howard\'s story \"Black Colossus\", however, has a princess 
			vocally directed by Mitra to make Conan her champion.[2] Crom makes no such appearances. In Conan stories by 
			authors other than Howard there is some evidence that Crom may exist. For example, in The Return of Conan, Crom 
			intervenes directly to save Conan from death and eternal damnation. See also John Maddox Roberts. Conan the 
			Valorous (Kindle Location 105).\n\n
			
			[1] Queen of the Black Coast by Robert E. Howard\n
			[2] Black Colossus by Robert E. Howard
        </item>
        <item>
            Dagon is a deity who presides over the Deep Ones, an amphibious humanoid race indigenous to Earth\'s oceans. 
            He is first introduced in Lovecraft\'s short story \"Dagon\", and is mentioned extensively throughout the mythos. 
            Also known as Father Dagon, he is a Great Old One and the consort of Mother Hydra.\n\n

			He is worshipped by the Esoteric Order of Dagon, a secret cult based in Innsmouth.\n\n
			
			Dagon is depicted as a gigantic Deep One (around 30 stories tall) and first appeared in the short story \"Dagon\"
			 - since then he and his consort have more or less been established as the official rulers of the Deep Ones, 
			 though Mother Hydra seems to gain a slightly larger following.  \n\n
			 
			 Lovecraft most likely based Dagon on the ancient Mesopotamian deity of the same name, who was a god of fish, 
			 fishing and fertility. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Ghatanothoa is a Great Old One and the firstborn of Cthulhu. It is a huge, amorphous monstrosity, whose appearance 
            is so hideous that anyone who gazes upon it (or even a perfect replica) is petrified into a living mummy. The 
            victim is permanently immobilized, the body taking on the consistency of leather and the internal organs and 
            brain preserved indefinitely, yet remains fully aware. Only the destruction of the subject\'s brain can free it 
            from its hellish prison, though the unfortunate is likely to be incurably insane long before the welcomed release.\n\n

			Ghatanothoa is currently trapped underneath Mount Yaddith-Gho in sunken Mu. He was brought to Earth from the 
			planet Yuggoth by an ancient, alien race, possibly the Mi-go, who built a colossal fortress atop Yaddith-Gho and 
			sealed Ghatanothoa inside the mountain beneath a large trapdoor. Ghatanothoa was worshipped by the ancient Muvians, 
			who both feared and respected him because of his ability to turn any humans that beheld him into living, thinking 
			mummies. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Hastur, known more commonly as \"Hastur the Unspeakable,\" is a Cthulhu mythos deity. Although the being is most 
            famously associated with Lovecraft it is only mentioned in one of his stories, \“The Whisperer in Darkness.\” 
            Originally it was the creation of Ambrose Bierce. Bierce\'s short story \"Haïta the Shepherd\" describes Hastur 
            as a god of shepherds. Hastur is the name of a city in the Robert W. Chambers short stories \“The Yellow Sign\” 
            and \“The Repairer of Reputations\” which appeared in his short story collection The King in Yellow. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Mother Hydra is a creature who, alongside her consort Dagon, is said to rule over the race known as the Deep Ones. \n\n

			There is debate as to whether or not Mother Hydra is a lesser Great Old One or merely a grotesquely mutated Deep 
			One - though the latter seems more likely as she doesn\'t seem to show much in the way of supernatural power 
			outside her gigantic size and unnaturally long life span. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Nug and Yeb, the Twin Blasphemies, are the spawn of Shub-Niggurath and Yog-Sothoth. Nug is the parent of 
            Cthulhu[1] and the parent of Kthanid via the influence of Yog-Sothoth. Nug is a god among ghouls, while Yeb is 
            the leader of Abhoth\'s alien cult.[2] Both Nug and Yeb closely resemble Shub-Niggurath.\n\n

			The names Nug and Yeb are similar to the names of the Egyptian sibling gods Nut and Geb, members of the 
			Heliopolitan Ennead.\n\n
			
			[1] Lovecraft, H. P. (1967). Selected Letters of H. P. Lovecraft IV (1932–1934). Sauk City, Wisconsin: Arkham House. "Letter 617". ISBN 0-87054-035-1.\n\n
			[2] Harms, \"Nug and Yeb\", Encyclopedia Cthulhiana, pp. 216–7.
        </item>
        <item>
            Nyarlathotep, known to many by his epithet \"The Crawling Chaos,\" is an Outer God in the Cthulhu Mythos. He is 
            the creation of H. P. Lovecraft and first appeared in his prose poem \"Nyarlathotep\" (1920). Nyarlathotep appears 
            in numerous subsequent stories by Lovecraft, and is also featured in the works of other authors.\n\n     

			Nyarlathotep differs from other Outer Gods in a number of ways. Most of them are exiled to the stars, like 
			Yog-Sothoth and Hastur, or are sleeping and dreaming like Cthulhu; Nyarlathotep, however, is active and frequently 
			walks the Earth in the guise of a human being, usually a tall, slim, joyous man. He has \"a thousand\" other 
			forms, most reputed to be quite horrific and sanity-blasting.\n\n

			Most of the Outer Gods have their own cults serving them; Nyarlathotep seems to serve these cults and take care 
			of their affairs in their absence. Most Outer Gods use strange alien languages, while Nyarlathotep uses human 
			languages and can be mistaken for a human being. Finally, most of them are all powerful yet evidently without 
			clear purpose, yet Nyarlathotep seems to be deliberately deceptive and manipulative, and even uses propaganda 
			to achieve his goals. In this regard, he is probably the most human-like among them.\n\n

			Nyarlathotep enacts the will of the Outer Gods, and is their messenger, heart and soul; he is also the servant 
			of Azathoth, whose fitful, spastic wishes he immediately fulfills. Unlike the other Outer Gods, causing madness 
			is more important and enjoyable than death and destruction to Nyarlathotep. It is suggested by some that he will 
			destroy the human race and possibly the earth as well. [1] \n\n
			
			[1] Harms, \"Nyarlathotep\", The Encyclopedia Cthulhiana, pp. 218–9.
			
        </item>
        <item>
            Shub-Niggurath (The Black Goat of the Woods with a Thousand Young) is an Outer God in the Cthulhu mythos of 
            H. P. Lovecraft. The being first appeared in Lovecraft\'s revision story \"The Last Test\" (1928); however, in 
            Lovecraft\'s fiction, she is never actually described, but is frequently mentioned or called upon in incantations. 
            Shub-Niggurath also appears in the works of other mythos authors, including August Derleth, Lin Carter, and Brian 
            Lumley. \n\n
            
            Shub-Niggurath is an Outer God in the pantheon. She is a perverse fertility deity, said to appear as an enormous 
            cloudy mass which extrudes black tentacles, slime-dripping mouths, and short, writhing goat legs. Small creatures 
            are continually spat forth by the monstrosity, which are either reconsumed into the miasmatic form or escape to 
            some monstrous life elsewhere. 
        </item>
        <item>
            The Demon-God of Xuthal[1] 	An octopoid monster of Hyborian Age which haunts the underground of Xuthal city.
            
            [1] Though not officially related as Great Old One, this entity is introduced by Robert E. Howard as 
            \"demon-god\", very similar to Lovecraft\'s Great Old Ones.
        </item>
        <item>
            Meaning \"The Most Ancient and Prolonged of Life\", it is also said as Tawil At-U\'mr or Tawil-at\'Umr. It is 
            described as an avatar of Yog Sothoth in the story \"Through the Gates of the Silver Key\". He presides over 
            the timeless halls beyond the Gate of the Silver Key and the strange Ancient Ones that dwell there. He is 
            described as the silhouette of a man behind a strange, shimmering veil. He is one of very few benign 
            Lovecraftian Great Old Ones who does not cause insanity in those who view him. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Y\'golonac, known as The Defiler, is a Great Old One. He is the god of perversion and depravity – not just 
            \"average\" human perversions or depravities, but any that can be conceived of by a sapient being (sane or 
            otherwise). His demeanor is much like that of Nyarlathotep, but he is much more perverse and sadistic. Y\'golonac 
            can sometimes be summoned merely by reading his name in the Revelations of Gla\'aki.\n\n

			Y\'golonac is imprisoned behind a wall of bricks in unknown ruins. His true form is uncertain, but when he 
			possesses a human host to manifest, he appears as a grotesquely obese man, lacking a head or neck, with a mouth 
			in the palm of each hand. Unlike other deities, Y\'golonac is clearly capable of understanding humans, to the point 
			of being able to conduct a conversation in English through his human host.

			Y\'golonac seeks humans who read perverse and forbidden literature to become his servants. When Y\'golonac is 
			summoned, he offers to grant the summoner the dubious honor of becoming his priest, or simply kills him for food. 
        </item>
        <item>
            Yig (the Father of Serpents) first appeared in the story The Curse of Yig which was created by Zealia Bishop and 
            almost completely rewritten by H. P. Lovecraft. He is a deity that appears as a serpent man, serpent with bat like 
            wings, or as a giant snake. Although Yig is easy to anger, he is easy to please as well. Yig often sends his 
            serpent minions, the children of Yig, to destroy or transform his enemies. He is associated with the Serpent Men.\n\n

			To Native Americans, Yig is regarded as \"bad medicine\". He is also alluded to in western American folklore. He 
			is identified with the Mesoamerican deity Quetzalcoatl, and may be a prototype for that god and other serpentine 
			gods worldwide. Some authors identify him as the Stygian serpent god Set\'s father, and from Robert E. Howard\'s 
			Conan stories, and also with the Great Serpent worshiped by the Serpent People of Valusia from Howard\'s Kull 
			stories.
        </item>
        <item>
            \"Yog-Sothoth knows the gate. Yog-Sothoth is the gate. Yog-Sothoth is the key and guardian of the gate. Past, 
            present, future, all are one in Yog-Sothoth. He knows where the Old Ones broke through of old, and where They 
            shall break through again. He knows where They have trod earth\'s fields, and where They still tread them, and 
            why no one can behold Them as They tread.\" [1] \n\n
            
            Its parent was the Nameless Mist. It is the parent of Cthulhu, Hastur the Unspeakable and the ancestor of the 
            Voormi. It is also the father of Wilbur Whateley.\n\n

			It is heavily implied, if not outright stated, that Yog-Sothoth is omniscient, and is locked outside the universe, 
			meaning he knows and can see all of space-time all at once, that there is no secret hidden from Yog-Sothoth. \n\n

			Like many Lovecraftian gods, Yog-Sothoth has many different appearances throughout the various stories of the 
			mythos, by various authors. However, there seems to common agreement that Yog-Sothoth visually manifests as a 
			mass of glowing orbs, with eyes or tendrils in some versions, and in others, simply the orbs. \n\n 
            
            [1] H. P. Lovecraft, \"The Dunwich Horror\"
        </item>
        <item>
            
        </item>
    </array>
</resources>
